<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Hardware | Not Quite Beta]]></title>
  <link href="http://notquitebeta.github.io/blog/categories/hardware/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://notquitebeta.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-01-03T19:37:22-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://notquitebeta.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[NQB]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[feedback@notquitebeta.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[A different way of thinking about power.]]></title>
    <link href="http://notquitebeta.github.io/2013/07/07/A_different_way_of_thinking_about_power"/>
    <updated>2013-07-07T11:36:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://notquitebeta.github.io/2013/07/07/A_different_way_of_thinking_about_power</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;ve had the new Macbook Air (2013) with the Haswell CPU for a little over a week now.  My last Macbook Air had a battery that was supposed to last 4.5 hours but practically lasted about 3 hours. Part of that could have been because I was always hitting the limit of the RAM and pages were being cached to disk.  Running the same constellation of apps, I can see that I&rsquo;m usually using more than the 2GB of built in memory I had.  At times, I&rsquo;ve spiked to 4 GB now.</p>

<p>With the new latop, I usually will get over 10 hours of battery life, I think.  It&rsquo;s hard to say because the calculation varies quite a bit.  The battery icon in the menu bar is no longer meaningful becuase it may look like there is 30% left but still have over 4 hours remaining.  Here is a view of the battery status.</p>

<p><img src="images/2013-07-07-battery.png" alt="battery" /></p>

<p>For those that may be wondering, this is an <a href="http://www.alfredapp.com">Alfred2</a> workflow using a <a href="http://www.alfredforum.com/topic/1211-battery-view-summary-stats-about-your-laptop-battery/">battery workflow</a> which can be obtained from <a href="https://dl.dropbox.com/u/2377432/alfredv2/battery/Battery.alfredworkflow">here</a> (Thanks Benzi!).</p>

<p>The change this brought on is that I&rsquo;m not always hovering close to my power sourse.  Usually, when I&rsquo;m working on the couch at night, I am checking my battery status and will have to stop when I get down to less than 10% and I start planning accordingly when I get down to 30%.  Now, the laptop is like an iPad or iPhone where I charge it and just carry it around.  I&rsquo;ll leave it on the dinner table all day while at work without worrying that the battery will be drained when I get home.  I&rsquo;ve had it unplugged for days during the work week without a problem, plugging it in when there was still 40% power remaining.  The amazing part is that I can recharge (not fully) in an hour and be good for another day.</p>

<p>It&rsquo;s simply a different way to think about a laptop.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
